Now, this course
is about React, but it is worth noting
that there are alternatives to React.js.
Now we're going to focus on React here and React is one
of the most popular front-end frameworks
or libraries, however, you want to call it you can learn.
It's a lean and focused component-based UI library.
It really focuses on this component thing,
and it doesn't have a lot of other features built in.
If you need our features like routing which we are,
of course, going to learn about in detail in this course
then you need to install a extra third-party library.
And that will sometimes be the case when working with React,
that you need to install third-party libraries
to add certain pieces of functionality to your application
because React itself really just focuses
on these components, which we're going
to learn about in greater detail later,
what exactly they are and how we create them,
and how it then renders these components,
and your user interface onto the screen.
That's the focus of React and extra functionality
which you might need for your React app,
therefore, sometimes has to be added
with help of some third-party package.
Now, an alternative to React, which has
more built in features would be Angular
another very important,
and very popular front-end framework.
And I got a course on this as well.
Angular is a complete component-based UI framework.
So, it also focuses on components just like React,
but it ships more built in features than React.
It also embraces TypeScript right from the start.
And it can be overkill for smaller projects,
therefore, since it has way more features built in.
But for a large project, on the other hand,
you don't need to rely on the community as much
because there's more built into that framework.
So, that's simply a little consideration you have to make.
The syntax also looks a bit differently
because, whilst it is component focused,
building these components works a bit differently
with Angular than it does with React.
Again, I got a course on that,
if you want to check out Angular as well.
And we also have another very popular framework,
another popular alternative and that would be Vue.js.
Vue.js is kind of like the mixture of Angular and React,
in between those two extremes,
if you want to call it like this.
It's also a complete component-based UI framework.
And it also includes a lot of features,
but a bit less features than Angular, but more than React.
It includes core features like routing, for example,
and therefore with Vue, you also have
to rely less on the community and still you don't have
as much overload possibly as you might have with Angular,
depending on what you build.
I also got a more detailed comparison video
on these three technologies,
in case you're interested in that.
Now, all three are super popular.
React currently is probably the most popular,
but all three are great, I got courses
on all three and therefore checking
those out might be a good idea as well.
But this course, of course, is about React
and therefore let's not lose any time, let's dive right in.